Guide to the Yale College Diplomae Examinatorium
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale College Diplomae examinatorium
1748-1758
RU 489
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
(1 box)
The materials consist of diplomae examinatorium of Yale College. The diplomae were read at commencement and include a formal greeting from the president of the college and a list of candidates for degrees. The diplomae are written in Latin and signed by the president.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 47 (YRG 47), Collections documenting teaching and learning in Yale academic programs.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Scope and Contents
The materials include Latin documents which were read aloud at the commencement exercises of Yale College, 1753-1860. Each diploma contains a formal greeting from the president, faculty, and assembly by the head of the academy and a list of the candidates for degrees. Each document was signed and witnessed by the president and faculty representative and dated.
Commencement ceremonies; Yale College (1718-1887) -- Students
- Diplomae Examinatorium, 1753-1860; Series I
  - Diplomae Examinatorium
    - President Thomas Clap, (1740-)1745-1766
      - 1753, 1755, 1762 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
    - President Naphtali Daggett, 1766-1777
      - 1769, 1770, 1775, 1776 (Box 1, Folder 4-7)
    - President Ezra Stiles, 1778-1795
      - 1778, 1781, 1789, 1790, 1792 (Box 1, Folder 8-12)
    - President Timothy Dwight, 1795-1817
      - 1798, 1800, 1805 (Box 1, Folder 13-15)
      - 1810-1814 (Box 1, Folder 16-20)
      - 1815? (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - 1816 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - President Jeremiah Day, 1817-1846
      - 1817 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - 1819, 1821-1846 (Box 1, Folder 24-50)
    - President Theodore Dwight Woolsey, 1846-1871
      - 1849-1850 (Box 1, Folder 51-52)
      - 1859-1860 (Box 1, Folder 53-54)
  - Orations
    - Undated Latin addresses 8 variations on " Anno iterum exacto (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Undated Latin addresses 3 variations on " Rederunt, cum hoc die academica (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Undated Latin address-" Anno acrum verso (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Fragments
    - Undated diploma fragment" Quos omnes in lingua edoctis " signed by Tutor Williams (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Undated oration fragment Nunc nebum fortiter et feliciter gestin (Box 1, Folder 59)